Guide to the University Faculty records, 1909-1998.
University Faculty records, 1909-1998
- Series I. Dean of the Faculty Records (11-1)
  - Collection 11-1-1616 (Box 1-5)
    - Minority Education Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Minority Education Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Music Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Nominations and Elections Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Personnel Planning & Policy Board, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Physical Education Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Professional & Economic Status Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Recombinant DNA Research Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Research Policies Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Review & Procedures Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - University - ROTC Relationships Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Budget, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Constituent Assembly, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - General Legislation, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Memorial Statements of the Faculty, 1976-1978 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Student Records Rehabilitation Project, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Series II. Faculty Minutes (11-5)
  - Collection 11-2-707 (Box 1-6)
    - correspondence, memos, minutes of Faculty Council, includes copies of some reports presented at meetings, 1955-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - minutes, memos, agendas, and reports presented at faculty meetings, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "Drafts of faculty meet." notes and drafts of minutes, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - notes, agendas, reports, and minutes, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "Notes of Faculty Meets. Preliminary Reports", 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - condensation of minutes, 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "U. Fac. Minutes", 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Faculty Minutes 1953-1954 as approved" includes 1955-1960 calendar and reports presented to meetings, 1953-1954, 1955-1960 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Minutes 1954-1955 as approved" includes some reports presented to meetings (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Faculty Minutes 1955-1956 approved" includes reports presented to meetings (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Faculty Minutes 1956-1957 approved" includes memos and reports presented (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "By-Laws of Cornell University as Adopted June 13, 1955" includes reports (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - corresondence and reports of university faculty, 1936, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - supplements to minutes, 1954-1957 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - "working mat. 1956-1957" notes and drafts of minutes, 1953, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - "correspondence HMH" carbons of Hazel M. Hauck's correspondence as secretary of the faculty (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - "Correspondence Faculty minutes", 1958 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - "Faculty Committees" correspondence and reports of committees to the faculty, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - "Faculty-Misc. Comm." report of Faculty Committee on the Scheduling of Public Events, May 27, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - "Com. on Negotiations" correspondence of the negotiations committee, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Reports to the Faculty, 1956-1960 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - "Rough Notes - Faculty" (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - "Notes on the Form of Faculty Minutes", 1951-1954 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - notes on faculty deliberations, Addendum to the Minutes of the Faculty Meeting of May 30, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - "Policy - U.-Corp. Relationships" Report of the Committee on University Policy on University-Corporation Relationships (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Minutes - minutes and memos about the faculty meetings, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - notes, minutes of faculty meetings, reports to university faculty, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - "Faculty Council - September 1960---" Paul VanRiper files as secretary of Faculty Council, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - notes, agendas, minutes, and reports of Faculty Council, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - memos, reports, minutes of University Faculty, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Collection 11-2-926 (Box 1-3)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1868 - 1872 (Box 1)
      Handwritten bound volume
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1872 - 1883 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1883 - 1891 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1891 - 1896 (Box 1)
      Handwritten until Fall 1895, then it becomes typescript
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, (pp. -271), 1896 - 1904 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, (pp.272-554), 1904 - 1912 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, (pp.555-914), Oct. 1912 - June 1917 (Box 2)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, (pp.915-1293), Oct. 1917 - June 1922 (Box 2)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, (pp.1294-1510), Oct. 1922 - June 1927 (Box 2)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, (pp.1511-1742), Oct. 1927 - June 1932 (Box 2)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, (pp.1743-1990), Oct. 1932 - June 1937 (Box 2)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, (pp.1991-2216), Oct. 1937 - May 1942 (Box 2)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, (pp.2217-2459), Aug. 1942 - June 1947 (Box 2)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, (pp.2460-2667), Oct. 1947 - June 1952 (Box 2)
    - Committee on University Policy- General (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Committee on University Policy, 1932-1942 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - A.A.U.P, 1944-1949 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Cornell University- Historical Items Notes of Interest, 1923, 1940-45, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Day, Edmund E., 1940-1951 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Vol. I- Minutes of the Committee on University Policy, 8/26/1943-2/16/1944 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Vol. II- Minutes of the Committee on University Policy, 2/23/1944-4/5/1944 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Vol. III- Minutes of the Committee on University Policy, 4/18/1944-5/6/1944 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - University Policy, Committee on (Minutes), 1951-1953 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - University Policy, Committee on (Minutes), 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Applications for Secretarial and Clearical Positions, April 1942 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Associations of Colleges and Universiuties- New York State (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Alpha Zeta (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - (B) Dean of the University Faculty- Administrative Correspondence, 1941-1955 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Blanding, Sarah G., 1941 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Books to be Considered for Order, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Blanding, Sarah G.- Correspondence with Dean Betten & Dean Murdock, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - (C) Dean of University Faculty- Administrative Correspondence, 1939-1948 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Cornell Co-op (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Cornell Co-op (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - (D) Dean of University Faculty- Administrative Correspondence, 1941-1952 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Meeting of Dean of Men of Central NYS Colleges, 1934-1941 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - (E) Dean of University Faculty- Administrative Correspondence, 1940-1947 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - (F) Dean of University Faculty- Administrative Correspondence, 1941-1949 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Faculty- Clippings and Items of Interest Concerning Faculty Members, 1940-1942 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - (G) Dean of University Faculty- Administrative Correspondence, 1941-1952 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - (H) Dean of University Faculty- Administrative Correspondence, 1941-1951 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - (I,J,K) Dean of University Faculty- Administrative Correspondence, 1940-1950 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - International Organization for Educational & Cultural Cooperation, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - (L) Dean of University Faculty- Administrative Correspondence, 1941-1949 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Ladd, Carl E., 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Land Grant & College Unity, 1939-1942 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Land Grant Colleges, Association of, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - (M) Dean of University Faculty- Administrative Correspondence, 1941-1952 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Malott, Dean W. (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Manning, C.D. (Proctor)- Also old correspondence from former proctor, 1931-1946 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Meigs, R.B., 1948 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Miller, J. Hillis, Associate Commissioner, State Department of Education, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - (N) Dean of University Faculty- Administrative Correspondence, 1941-1949 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - National Roster of Scientific & Specialized Personel, April 1942 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - New York State Associations of Deans, Oct. 1940 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - NYS Department of Education, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - (O) Dean of University Faculty- Administrative Correspondence, 1941-1943 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Ogden, R. M., Feb. 19, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - (P) Dean of University Faculty- Administrative Correspondence, 1940-1951 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Phi Kappa Phi, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - (R) Dean of University Faculty- Administrative Correspondence, 1940-1951 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Room Reservations, 1940-1942 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Rural Institute for Religious Workers, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - (S) Dean of University Faculty- Administrative Correspondence, 1940-1949 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Secretary of the University, 1944-45 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - State Universities, National Association of, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - (T) Dean of University Faculty- Administrative Correspondence, 1941-1949 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Tarshis, Lorie- "The Elements of Economics" (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Underwater Sound Laboratory, 1942-1948 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - (V) Dean of University Faculty- Administrative Correspondence, 1940-1948 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - (W) Dean of University Faculty- Administrative Correspondence, 1940-1948 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - (Z) Dean of University Faculty- Administrative Correspondence, Dec. 12, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Zoology I- Outline Submitted by Prof. Young, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - University Faculty Committee on Student Affairs, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Committee on Academic Freedom & Tenure- Minutes, 12/5/57 - May 1959 (Box 3, Folder 62)
- Series III. Standing Committees (11-5)
  - 11-5-1740 (Box 1-5)
    - Academic Freedom and Responsibility Committee, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Academic Integrity Hearing Board, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Academic Integrity Appeals Board, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Academic Programs and Policies Committee, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Academic Records & Instuction Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Admissions & Financial Aids Committee, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Calendar Committee, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Committee Assignments, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Committees, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Economic Status of the Faculty, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Executive Committee of the FCR, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Freedom of Teaching & Learning Committee, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - International Student Affairs Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Lectures Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Membershp of the University Faculty, Committee on, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Music Committee, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Nominations & Elections Committee, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Professional & Economic Status, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Research Policies Committee, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Review and Procedures Committee, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - University-ROTC Relationships Committee, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Balloting, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Ballots, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Budget, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Budget, Dean of Faculty, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Faculty, New, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - FCR & Faculty Meetings, Material for (Agenda), 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - General Legislation Work Copies, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Memorial Statements, Work Papers, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Academic Freedom and Responsibility Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Subcommittee - Faculty Member's Responsibilities, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Academic Programs and Policies Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Subcommittee - Evaluation of Centers, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Subcommittee - Center for International Studies, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Subcommittee - Land Grand Report, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Academic Records and Instruction Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Subcommittee, 1973-1976 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Budget Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Executive Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Faculty and FCR Meetings, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Human Affairs Program, 1971-1976 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Independent Courses, Committee on, 1974-1977 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Background Material, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - International Student Affairs Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Library Board, 1975-1979 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Membership Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Memorial Statements of the Faculty, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Military Curricula Committee, 1960-1969 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Minority Education Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Music Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Physical Education Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Physical Education and Athletics, November 1956 - May 1972 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Professional & Economic Status Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Subcommittee on Grievance, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Recombinant DNA Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Registration and Schedules Minutes, November 1967 - September 1972 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Research Policies Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Review and Procedures Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - University-ROTC Relationships Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 30)